What the…
搞什么？
There. Get in place!
乖一点
CONSTRUCTION - NO TRESPASSING
（施工中 禁止进入）
What do you think you're doing? No trespassing! It's dangerous!
你在做什么？不能进来 很危险
-I just want to touch it. -Are you insane?
-我只是想摸一下 -你疯了吗？
You can't do that!
你不能过去
But you see, unless I touch the willow tree, I can't go to school.
如果没摸到柳树 我就没办法上学
That's my rule.
这是我的原则
Hey! Watch out! It's dangerous! Are you insane?
喂 小心啊 很危险 你疯了吗？
Hey! Stop!
喂 站住
Even if I told them,
就算我这样跟他们说
there's no way these guys would understand.
他们也不可能理解的
Yes!
好耶！
Two minutes to the convenience store? Piece of cake!
两分钟到便利商店？小菜一碟
Hey! Stop!
喂 站住
To me, everything in this world is just a game.
对我来说 世间的一切 都只是一场游戏
Assemble!
集合
You see,
虽然
even though nobody will admit it, unless you think like that,
不会有人承认 但如果不这么想
we can't deal with this crap.
根本就无法应付这种无聊事
Where's your enthusiasm? Do it over!
你们的活力上哪去啦？重来
Yes, sir!
好的
Assemble!
集合
Do it over!
重来
Too slow! Do it over!
太慢啦 重来
You remember the S irregular conjugation, right?
还记得S不规则动词变化吗？
"Su," "se," "shi," "su," "suru," "sure," "seyo."
su se shi su suru sure seyo
With that in mind, let's go over this again.
记住这个原则 我们重新整理一遍
Understand? Good.
懂了吗？很好
And finally, Let's see…
最后 让我们看看…
Every day is nothing but repetition of totally meaningless stuff.
每天不断重复毫无意义的事情
You didn't know?
你不知道？
Well, you see…
所以说
There are guys who only ever talk about stuff they saw on TV
有些家伙只会谈论电视上看到的东西
that make you want to say, "Who gives a damn?"
让人只想说“关我屁事？”
What the heck are you drinking?
你在喝什么？
Dokodemo Honey.
任意门蜂蜜
What's that?
那是什么？
Food for rhinoceros beetles.
独角仙的饲料
There are also a wide variety of nut jobs.
还有各式各样的疯子
When everyone's a bunch of brats,
当大家都是一群乳臭未干的小鬼时
you're worse off if you're sane.
如果你还有理智 情况就很会更糟
-Shuji! -Yes?
-修二 -干吗？
-Want to do karaoke today? -Let's go!
-今天要不要一起去唱歌？ -一起去呀
Give me a break, you jerks!
少烦我 你们这些混蛋
You still haven't paid me back when I paid for you guys last time.
上次帮你们付的唱歌钱 到现在还没还我
-You bet! -Cool!
-当然啦 -酷
Oh, crap.
糟糕
Our homeroom teacher, Yokoyama, wants to see me after school today.
今天放学 班主任横山找我过去
-What? It's no fun without you! -What about me?
-什么？没你就不好玩你啦 -那我呢？
-The usual place, right? -Yes.
-老地方 对吗？ -对
I'll be there when I'm done.
我忙完就过去
You could wait a million years, but I'll never show up.
你们等一百万年 我也不会出现的
And don't sing my song!
不准唱我的歌哦
If I play my cards right and keep up my status,
只要我处理妥当 保持现在的地位
I can make it through without getting hurt.
就能毫发无伤地直到最后
Okay. Let's play the kind of cool
好啦 今天也要扮得酷一点
but helpful Shuji Kiritani to the hilt again today.
热心助人的桐谷修二
Even this perfect guy that I am
但就连这么完美的我
has an enemy.
也有天敌
Found you!
找到你啦
Kusano…
草野
Hey! I heard that God is dead.
喂 听说上帝死了
-Who said that crap? -Nietzsche!
-你听谁在胡说八道？ -尼采
The philosopher Nietzsche said it.
是哲学家尼采说过的话
But can God even die? I mean, what would the cause of death even be?
但上帝会死吗？死因是什么？
Hey, come on. Don't ignore me.
喂 别这样 不要不理我啊
-I know I'm the only one you confide in. -Listen!
-我知道你只跟我说心事 -我说啊
Don't tell anyone.
别告诉任何人
-We're friends, right? -No, we're not!
-我们是朋友 对吗？ -才不是
Now you just listen to me.
你给我听好
We're not friends or nothing!
我们不是朋友 什么都不是
Oh, come on.
拜托
Why are you still so upset?
那你为什么这么生气？
Okay then. Can I tell you something as a friend?
好 我能以朋友的身份告诉你一件事吗？
Sure.
当然
You know how you flap your arms when you come down the stairs?
你刚刚下楼梯时是不是 这样手舞足蹈？
-I do not do that. -Yes, you do!
-我才没有 -明明就有
-Toss that. -What?
-帮我丢掉 -什么？
I told you to cut out the flapping!
我不是叫你别再跳了吗？
I hate that guy's guts.
真是讨厌的家伙
It's gone.
不见了
The willow's gone! How come?
柳树不见了 为什么？
It's gone! The willow's gone!
不见了 柳树不见了
It's gone! The willow's gone! How come?
不见了 柳树不见了 为什么？
This was the only place I could find comfort!
这是我唯一能得到安慰的地方
Hey! Fish! Why is it gone?
喂 小鱼 怎么不见啦？
Tell me!
告诉我啊
Willow tree! Where are you? Are you here somewhere?
柳树 你在哪里？在附近吗？
Willow tree!
柳树
You're kidding!
开玩笑
Wait…
不会吧
Are you the willow sprite?
你是柳树精吗？
What?
什么？
What? What do you want?
什么？你想怎样？
Hey! What do you want?
喂 你想怎样？
The willow…
那棵柳树
If you're looking for it, it's gone.
如果你在找它 它不见啦
It was pulled up by the roots this afternoon and carried off.
今天下午它被连根拔起带走啦
Is that right?
是吗？
Since it was a willow tree, it wasn't really suited for hanging.
不过那是棵柳树 不太适合上吊
Since it sways and rustles, it seems otherworldly.
它摇摇晃晃 沙沙作响 有种异次元的感觉
That's why I liked it.
所以我很喜欢
Do you have a stomachache?
请问你肚子痛吗？
No. Why?
没有 怎么这么问？
The expression on your face made it look that way.
你的脸色不太好
I was smiling.
我是在笑啊
That was smiling?
那是笑吗？
Smiling?
你笑了吗？
The day the willow was pulled up
柳树被拔起的那天
was the day she showed up.
就是她出现的那一天
The girl who seemed to hate
那个似乎…
everything in this world.
憎恨全世界的女孩
Thanks to this moron who believes everything in this world is for him,
多亏这个认为世上一切 都是为了他存在的笨蛋
my high-school life that had been peaceful until now,
我平稳的高中生活
gradually started to fall apart.
渐渐开始崩坏
I was stupid enough at the time to not even notice it was happening.
我竟然笨到没有察觉这件事
What that meant for me was…
那对我来说的意义是…
Actually, I don't want to talk about what happened next.
事实上 我不想谈接下来发生的事
-Morning!
-早安 -早
-Hello!
-大家好
Destiny! Nice to have you here!
-命运双人组 请多多指教
Did you hear?
你听说了吗？
The hot topic lately is Goyokudo.
最近的热门话题是豪翼堂
The bookstore on the shopping street.
就是商店街里的书店
The store that only allows beautiful men and women to read there.
是只准帅哥美女进去看书的店家
I heard Sebastian tried going there!
我听说赛巴斯汀曾去那里挑战过
That's right. The teacher Sebastian, who's actually timid,
没错 赛巴斯汀老师其实很胆小
he walked right up and tried!
竟大胆走上前去挑战啦
READING PROHIBITED EXCEPT FOR BEAUTIFUL MEN AND WOMEN
（禁止阅读 帅哥美女除外）
He lasted only seconds!
他只撑了几秒就被制止
-And that Bando tried reading there too! -That gaudy…
-然后坂东也尝试去那里看书 -那个花枝招展的家伙
That Bando foolishly tried as well!
坂东也傻傻地去挑战
Hey! Let me in!
喂 让我进去
What's your problem, you fucking geezer?
臭老头 你有什么毛病？
-You okay? -Fucking geezer!
-你还好吗？ -死老头
Prick!
混蛋
What's your fucking problem?
你有什么毛病？
The poor girl.
她真可怜
So he wouldn't even let her in?
所以他不让她进去？
-Yes. -Isn't that mean?
-对 -是不是很过分？
Isn't there anyone he lets read in his store?
他店里有人能进去看书吗？
-I doubt it. -Isn't there one?
-我很怀疑 -不是有一个人吗？
Who?
谁啊？
Mariko Uehara from Class A.
Ａ班的上原真理子
Mariko Uehara?
上原真理子啊？
That makes sense.
说得也是
Then I guess Mariko Uehara's era won't end yet.
所以上原真理子的时代还没结束
Big news! Transfer student!
天大的消息 有转学生
-No way! -Seriously?
-真的吗？ -真的假的？
-Boy? Girl? -Girl.
-是男生还是女生？ -女生
I heard she's prettier than Mariko Uehara.
听说比上原真理子还漂亮
-Seriously? -No way!
-真的吗？ -不会呀？
That's totally awesome!
那真是太棒啦
That means her position at the top will change!
那她第一名的宝座就要保不住啦？
Eight days a week, hello!
一周八天 大家好
Shuji, there's a transfer student.
修二 有转校生来啦
I already heard. I sent Tani to scout out the staff room.
我听说啦 我已经派阿谷去教师办公室调查
-You're the best, Shuji! -No problem!
-修二 最棒啦！ -那是当然啦
-You did it!
-成功啦！
Is she a hot babe?
是美人吗？
What's she like?
她长得怎么样？
If she were sushi, like uni?
如果用寿司比喻 是像海胆吗？
Like toro?
该不会是像金枪鱼腹？
What? Otoro?
是金枪鱼大腹肉吗？
No way!
怎么会？
-What's that? -Her ankle.
-那是什么？ -她的脚踝
-Ankle? -How can we tell from that?
-脚踝？ -那怎么看得出来？
Give us more details! What actress is she like?
说仔细一点 是像哪个女演员？
Akiko Yada!
矢田亚希子
-Akiko Yada?
-矢田？
You've never even seen Akiko Yada, so how can you say that?
你从没见过矢田亚希子 怎么能说得这么肯定？
You've never even seen the real deal!
你根本没看到她
-She is totally cute, man! -Okay! Fine!
-她真的超可爱 -我知道啦
The transfer student.
转学生
You took this?
这是你拍的？
By chance.
不小心拍到的
It's a miracle!
真是奇迹
Nice work, rhino beetle boy. I'll give you lots of honey later.
干得好 独角仙小子 我等一下会给你很多蜂蜜
I've got a photo of the transfer student!
拿到转学生的照片啦
-Seriously? -No way!
-真的吗？ -怎么可能？
-Give me that! -Let me see!
-给我 -让我看看
What a bunch of morons.
真是一群笨蛋
Yo! Here!
我来啦
Did you hear?
你们听说了吗？
You got more info?
你有更多情报吗？
Sebastian tried reading at Goyokudo.
赛巴斯汀想在豪翼堂看书
Good photo.
拍得不错
Hey!
喂 听好啦
Sebastian got the boot for reading there.
赛巴斯汀在那里看书被赶出去啦
What a real dummy, right?
是不是真的很蠢？
Come on! Listen! Okay, I'll explain it again.
听我说啊 我再说一次
It says only beautiful men and women can read there, but that idiot…
上面写只有帅哥美女才能在那里看书 但那个笨蛋…
What a moron.
那个蠢蛋
Don't tell Bando that.
别跟坂东说这件事啊
I guess he doesn't realize what he is. Right?
看来他搞不清楚 自己有几斤重 对吗？
-You jerk! -What? What is it?
-你这个混蛋！ -什么？怎么啦？
Don't fuck with me!
开什么玩笑
-Sorry! Okay! Help! -Stop, Kusano!
-抱歉 好啦 救命 -站住 草野
She's here! The transfer student!
她来啦 转学生
-The transfer student! -A transfer student? Really? No way!
-转学生 -转学生？真的吗？怎么会？
Good morning!
早安
Okay, get in your seats.
好啦 都回到座位上
Okay, time to take attendance.
我要开始点名啦
What about the transfer student?
老师 转学生在哪？
Oh, right. You're right.
对啦 没错
Transfer student!
转学生
Come on in.
请进
Come in.
进来
What? Wait!
什么？等等
That's not Akiko Yada!
不是矢田亚希子啊
No, James!
不 詹姆斯
-That's not Akiko Yada. -Quiet down!
-那不是矢田亚希子 -安静
Quiet down!
安静下来
The willow…
柳树…
You know Kiritani?
你认识桐谷吗？
She says she doesn't know you.
她说不认识你啊
Shuji Kiritani is in such shock. He's seized up.
桐谷修二受到冲击 动弹不得
Who's that supposed to be?
就是说啊
Okay. Why don't you introduce yourself? Okay?
那你自我介绍一下
This is Nobuko Kotani.
这位是小谷信子
Why don't you tell us your hobby or something?
跟我们说说你的兴趣
I don't have one.
没有
Plans for your future or a club you want to join?
有没有对未来的计划 或是想加入的社团？
-None. -None? I see.
-没有 -没有啊
Okay. All right.
好的 了解
All right, everyone. Let's make her feel welcome.
好 那大家要好好跟她相处
As for your seat, second from the back, two rows from the window is open.
座位的话 靠窗第二排倒数第二个座位没人坐
What?
什么？
I'm sitting here.
我要坐这里
Bando, when did you start sitting there?
坂东 你什么时候坐在那里啦？
Ages ago.
很久以前
Then go back to your original seat.
那就坐回你原本的座位
Why do I have to move?
为什么要我换座位
Now, now. Don't complain. All right?
别抱怨 好吗？
Go on back.
回去
Sit at the empty desk.
你就坐在空位上
Okay.
好
I'll take attendance now.
我要点名啦
-Aoi. -Here!
-苍井 -在
-Akashi. -Here.
-明石
-Inoue. -Did you see that?
-井上 -你们看到了吗？
-I saw it. -Yes, I saw that.
-看到啦 -对 我看到啦
Hey, you. You brushed off that desk like it was filthy.
喂 你刚刚擦那张桌子 是嫌它脏啊
You think it's dirty 'cause I sat there?
因为我坐过所以很脏吗？
Hey! Stop that!
给我停止
Get back to your seat!
回座位去
Kind of gloomy in here.
气氛不太好啊
Destiny, come up here.
命运双人组 上来
Do a gag to brighten things up.
来搞笑一下 让气氛轻松一点
-Oh, okay. -We'll do a new gag!
-好啊 -表演新段子
-Ready, go!
-预备
A little hat makes a "shoboshi."
戴上小帽子就变成“消防员”
I can't understand you at all! Disaster!
完全听不懂 灾难啊！
After the gag, don't look so worried. Okay?
你们表演完 不要露出这么担心的表情 好吗？
-But…
-但是…
-Oh, we're in sync!
-心有灵犀
-This must be destiny!
-这一定是命运
Enough. Sit!
够啦 坐下
Thank you very much, Destiny.
谢谢命运双人组
-Here we go. Kawai. -Here!
-继续点名 河合 -在
-Kimura. -Here.
-木村
-Kiritani.
-桐谷 -在
-Kusano. -Yo!
-草野 -在呀
I want you to try to work this one out on your own.
这次你们自己解出这一题
If the radius is 3.1…
如果半径是3.1…
Y touches these two points.
Ｙ碰触到这两点
And X needs to be up here.
Ｘ要在上面
"Isn't that chick creepy?"
“不觉得那女的很诡异吗？”
"Don't you think that chick is weird?"
“不觉得那女的怪怪的吗？”
"Don't you think that chick stinks?"
“不觉得那女的很臭吗？”
And what's negative three plus three?
负三加三等于多少？
Let's do that.
就这么办
What's for lunch today, Mariko?
真理子 今天的午餐是什么？
Broccoli dumplings.
西兰花烧麦
Broccoli?
西兰花？
He's got it! Manesuke!
出现啦 高级便当
That's totally manesuke.
完全就是高级便当
I envy you.
真羡慕你
Shuji!
修二
Your lady's here.
你女朋友来啦
Today's is really good.
我对今天的便当很有自信哦
Seriously?
真的假的？
-Okay. -Let's go.
-好 -走
Hey.
喂
Is Shuji dating Mariko Uehara?
修二和上原真理子在交往吗？
Why else would they always have lunch together?
不然他们为什么每天一起吃午餐？
A bento lunch made by Mariko Uehara…
上原真理子做的便当
Think we could net auction that?
可以到网上拍卖吗？
-Good idea! -What an idiot!
-好主意 -真蠢
It would go bad by the time the auction ended!
等拍卖完就馊掉啦
This looks awesome! Wow!
看起来好好吃 太厉害啦
Awesome!
好吃
I'm so glad to be alive.
活着真好
This is totally great!
超好吃
I heard the transfer student looks like Akiko Yada.
听说你们班的转学生 长得像矢田亚希子
No. That's a lie.
那是骗人的
She's kind of creepy.
那家伙有点诡异
Really?
真的吗？
This broccoli dumpling is awesome!
这个西兰花烧麦太好吃啦
You know what?
你知道吗？
That's where us girls always have our lunch.
我们原本都在这里吃午餐
Do you think you could move?
你可以让一让吗？
Hello? Can you hear us?
喂 听得见吗？
-Hello? -Something must be wrong with her.
-喂？ -她一定有什么毛病
Can't you hear?
听不见吗？
I'm sorry! I accidentally hit it!
对不起 我不小心撞到啦
I'm so sorry!
对不起
Sorry. I feel so bad. We should go.
对不起 我好抱歉 我们走啦
-Let's go. -Sorry.
-走 -抱歉 再见
-Say… -Don't do that.
-那个… -别过去
If you're not careful, we'll end up always having to eat with her.
不小心一点的话 我们以后都得跟她同桌吃饭啦
Oh, you're right.
是吗？
-What time you want to meet? -What?
-你想几点见面？ -什么？
Did you forget?
你忘了吗？
-You promised to go out today. -I remember. I swear it.
-今天不是约好了吗？ -我记得 我发誓
So what time?
几点？
I'm sorry! Really sorry!
对不起 真的很抱歉
There's something I absolutely have to go to today.
但我今天有事情非去处理不可
What is it?
什么事？
Actually…
其实…
It's a funeral.
我要参加葬礼
A funeral?
葬礼？
-Really? -Really.
-真的吗？ -真的
I swear it. See? Look at this.
我发誓 你看这个
You're right.
是真的
Sorry.
抱歉
-Let's do it a different day. -What?
-那我们改天约 -什么？
When's good?
要约什么时候？
When should we? Good question.
什么时候？真是个好问题
I'm looking for the place to toss out food.
我在找回收厨余的地方
There's no cooking practice today, so not in here.
今天没有烹饪课 所以不能丢这里
The incinerator!
焚化炉
You don't know where that is, do you?
你不知道在哪里 对吗？
-I'll take you. Okay? -What?
-我带你去 好吗？ -什么？
This is that new Akiko Yada girl in our class.
这位就是我们班新来的矢田亚希子
She doesn't know where it is, so I'll take her.
她不知道在哪里 所以我带她去
Let's go.
走吧
What actually happened to that?
到底发生什么事啦？
Someone ruined it, right?
是有人翻弄的 对吗？
Like Bando or them?
是坂东她们吗？
Well, it doesn't really matter to me. It's none of my business.
我是无所谓啦 不关我的事
FOOD SCRAPS
（厨余）
Shouldn't you go back?
你不回去吗？
Your girlfriend's waiting.
你女朋友在等你
It's okay.
没关系
I mean, she's not my girlfriend.
她不是我女朋友
What about the funeral?
葬礼？
Oh, that? That was a lie.
那个啊？那是骗人的
What about that necktie?
那领带？
I found it in the street on the way to school.
我在上学途中捡到的
I thought I could use it to get out of a promise I made.
我认为可以用来逃避我做出的承诺
Then
那么
don't make promises in the first place.
一开始不要做出承诺不就好了吗？
-I don't think… I could-- -She's right!
-我不认为我能… -她说得对
Catherine!
凯瑟琳
Kiritani.
桐谷
You won't always get away with making up stopgap lies, you know.
别以为编造敷衍了事的谎言 总能全身而退
What are you doing on the roof?
你在屋顶上做什么？
It's way too far to go through the main gate.
走正门太远啦
It's a waste of time.
太浪费时间
You. Educate this guy and make him into an honest person. Okay?
你啊 好好教育他 让他变成正直的人 好吗？
-Who's that? -The head teacher.
-那是谁？ -教务主任
The head teacher?
教务主任？
I thought she was a crow-billed tengu.
我以为她是鸦天狗
It's creepy.
好诡异
I heard it was some student's parent.
我听说是某个学生的家长
What's this about?
怎么啦？
-Here you go, Mr. Yokoyama. -Thank you.
-横山老师 -谢谢
Principal Iehara,
家原校长
some loser is climbing over our school's wall.
有个怪人爬墙进入我们学校
You're kidding.
你在开玩笑吧
I saw them too.
我也有看到
It was an older woman dressed like a youngster.
是个打扮年轻的老女人
How brazen!
真是不要脸
-No. I think it was… -What?
-不 我想那是… -什么？
-Nothing.
-你要说什么？ -没什么
I know!
-我是说… -我知道啦
The students are gossiping about it, aren't they?
学生们都在议论纷纷？
You know who it is?
你知道是谁吗？
No… Well…
不 那个…
What everyone says…
大家都说…
What do they say?
大家都说什么？
It's a crow-billed tengu.
那是鸦天狗
A crow-billed tengu? What's that?
鸦天狗？那是什么？
That's just what people say.
大家都那么说
It's gone.
不见啦！
My key is gone!
我的钥匙不见啦
Found you.
找到了
-I'm saved! -What do you want?
-我得救啦 -你想怎样？
I lost my bike key.
我把自行车的钥匙弄丢了
-So? -Let me ride on back.
-所以？ -让我坐后面
No way!
休想
Who said you could get on?
谁准你上车的？
Please stay behind the white line.
请退回到白线后方
Watch out! Let's go!
危险 出发
Don't grab onto me!
不要抓我
First it's a crow-billed tengu, now a Konaki-jiji?
先是鸦天狗 然后是子泣爷爷？
Hey! That Chinese cabbage is cheap!
喂 那颗白菜好便宜
Hey! It was on sale!
喂 在打折啊
Turn left there.
左转
Watch out! Oh, no! Watch out!
危险 不要啊 危险
Next stop, Hirayama Tofu Shop. Hirayama Tofu Shop.
下一站 平山豆腐店
-Want a drink? -A drink of what?
-要喝一杯吗？ -喝什么？
Mamechichi.
豆子乳
Welcome back.
回来啦
Mr. Hirayama, I'm taking two cups.
大叔 我要两杯
Mamechichi? You mean soymilk?
“豆子乳”？你是在说豆乳吗？
What? You mean this is called "soymilk"?
什么？这叫豆乳？
-Yes. -It's not "mamechichi"?
-对啊 -不是“豆子乳”吗？
Mr. Hirayama, how come you never told me?
大叔 你怎么没跟我说
Who cares what it's called.
叫什么有什么关系
As long as made good and proper.
东西的品质好就行啦
Hello.
你好
Fart!
放个屁
Is this your house?
这是你家吗？
No. My boarding house.
错 是我的寄宿处
Is your home far?
你家很远吗？
My home is on the top floor of that building.
我家在那栋大楼的顶楼
What?
什么？
That high-rise condo?
那栋高层公寓吗？
Your family's rich?
你家很有钱吗？
That's right.
答对啦
What's your dad do?
你爸是做什么的？
My dad is the president of the company
我爸在右边的那栋大楼
on the top floor of the building on the right.
顶楼的那间公司当社长
He's a president?
社长？
A president…
社长…
Yes. A president.
对啊 社长
Why are you down here with us?
那你为什么跟我们在这里混？
My dad told me,
我爸跟我说
"You'll run this company someday, so the fun ends at high school.
“你总有一天要继承公司 高中后就没有玩乐的日子啦
Enjoy your youth to the fullest! Leave no regrets!"
所以尽情享受青春 不要留下遗憾”
-Hurry up and choose a cake. -Just hold on a minute.
-快点选蛋糕啦 -等一下
I'm not sure what I'm supposed to do with my youth.
我还真不知道青春时该做什么
What I think is…
我认为
we do things that nobody else has ever done.
-是去做没人做过的事 -这样啊
And explore the limits of your abilities until you collapse.
探索能力的极限 直到崩溃为止
I think that's what it is.
我想就是这样
Then what should we do?
那我们该做什么？
Think of that on your own.
你自己想
Hurry up and choose one.
快点选一块蛋糕啦
I'm telling you…
我说啊
I don't care which one.
哪一块都无所谓
You know what?
你知道吗？
If you can't choose one, then you must not want either of them.
如果你选不出来 就代表你什么都不想要
You think?
是吗？
I'm leaving.
我要回去啦
Wait! Ouch!
等一下 好痛
I don't want either one? That's a possibility too.
什么都不想要？也是有这种可能啊
The scales fell from my eyes.
眼睛上的鳞片掉下来啦
Ouch!
好痛
I think a contact fell out.
隐形眼镜好像掉啦
Take care.
慢走
-Thanks. I will. -Hey! I lost a contact!
-好的 谢谢 -等等 我的隐形眼镜掉啦
It's late.
好晚啦
Shuji!
哥
What? What is it, Koji?
浩二 怎么啦？
-It's Mom! -What?
-是妈妈 -什么？
-Just hurry up and come with me! -What's wrong?
-快跟我来就对啦 -怎么啦？
-Hurry! -Watch out!
-快点 -小心
Hurry! Hurry up!
快点 快一点
Dad! You're home early.
爸 你回来的真早
Shuji!
修二
What? There was a plane crash?
什么？有飞机失事？
It's the one Mom was on.
妈妈就是坐的这架飞机
What? Seriously?
什么？真的吗？
Seriously? How do you know?
真的吗？你怎么知道？
-Her name. -Her name?
-她的名字 -她的名字？
-What? -These are possible Japanese passengers.
-什么？ -以下为疑似日本乘客的名单
Takafumi Kanayama.
金山贵文
Nobuko Kiritani.
桐谷信子
Wait!
等一下
Her phone! Her mobile phone!
电话 她的手机
-Call her mobile phone! Now! -Hurry!
-打她的手机 快点 -快点
Call her mobile phone now!
-快打她的手机
Forget it! I'll do it!
算啦 我来打
I'll do it!
我来打
Answer! Hurry! Answer!
快接啊 快点 快接电话
Why aren't you answering?
为什么不接电话？
HOME
（家里来电）
She's not answering.
她没接
Could this be…
这会不会是…
the call to confirm her death?
来通知她死讯的电话？
I can't.
不行
You answer it.
你去接
-Hurry up and answer it! -Hurry!
-快去接啊 -快点
Hello?
喂？
Mom? No way!
妈？怎么会？
How you doing?
还好吗？
"Where am I"? Nigeria.
我在哪里？我在尼日利亚啊
I'm working, you know.
我很认真在工作啊
Forget about that. What're you having for dinner?
不说这个啦 你晚餐吃什么？
Hold on.
等一下
Dinner! What's for dinner?
我们晚餐吃什么？
Hurry up and tell me!
快点告诉我
Gyoza.
饺子
Hello? Gyoza!
喂？饺子
Gyoza?
饺子？
Gyoza. Really? Gyoza?
吃饺子啊 真的吗？饺子？
He hung up.
他挂断啦
Gyoza? What's gyoza?
饺子？饺子是什么？
Well, you see, it's a delicious…
那是种很好吃…
What did Mom say?
妈怎么说？
She said, "Gyoza? Really? Gyoza?"
她说“饺子？真的吗？”
-That's all? -Yes.
-就这样？ -对
Oh, so she's alive…
她还活着
Koji! Let's eat! Let's eat dinner!
浩二 我们来吃晚餐
-She's alive? -Yes! She's alive!
-她还活着？ -对 她还活着
She's alive!
她还活着
Thank goodness!
太好啦
KOJI KIRITANI 6TH GRADE, CLASS 3
（六年三班 桐谷浩二）
Why a baby chick?
为什么是小鸡？
What does it matter? It just needs to cover the hole.
有什么关系？只要补好就行啦
But that's the same as Watanabe.
可是那就跟渡边一样啦
-I bet Watanabe's a girl, right? -There! It's ready.
-我猜渡边应该是女生？ -好啦 可以吃啦
That looks great!
看起来好美味
-That looks delicious. -All right! Gyoza!
-看起来好好吃 -好耶 饺子
-Hey! No fair eating one first! -Yum!
-不公平 你都先吃 -好吃
No fair!
不公平
But you know…
你们要知道
Somewhere on Earth right now,
此刻地球上的某处
there's a family in mourning.
有人的家中正在哀悼
-And here are some flowers. -There we go.
-把这些花插进去 -插进去啦
-How's that? -Looking good.
-怎么样？ -看起来很不错
-It's done! -Yay!
-完成啦 -好耶
Eight days a…
一周…
-Nice, right? -Yes. Very pretty.
-是不是不错？ -对 很漂亮
Those girls are taking this a little too far.
那些女生越来越过分啦
Don't you think that's pretty uncool?
你们不觉得这样很差劲吗？
It's just a joke. You like jokes. Right, Shuji?
只是开个玩笑 你不是喜欢开玩笑吗？修二
Yes, but that's not funny.
是啦 但这又不好笑
I mean, that's so lame!
这太逊了
-Lame? -Totally lame.
-逊？ -这很没意思
-It is not! -Come on. Break it up!
-才不会 -好啦 散会
-It is not lame. -Yes, it is lame.
-一点都不逊 -超逊的
You're the lame one.
你才逊啦
Bando, the comedy we like is surreal and dry humor.
坂东 我们喜欢的是 新奇又夸张的玩笑
Fine.
知道啦
-Okay? -Yes. You guys are lame.
-好吗？ -好啦 你们真没意思
-Surreal! -Yes, whatever.
-要够新奇哦 -随便啦
-He's always like that. -What jerks.
-他总是这样 -真讨厌
You died on your second day here.
你转来第二天就死啦
-You poor thing!
真可怜
-She ignoring us? -What's her problem?
-她无视我们 -搞什么？
She ticks me off. Let's go.
气死我啦 走
She's going to get torn to pieces.
她会被击垮的
-Shuji. -Yes?
-修二 -什么？
-Pass. -Right.
-传球 -好
Well, it's none of my business though.
但那也不关我的事
-Found you! -Don't touch me!
-找到你啦 -别碰我
-Hey. Wait. -What?
-等等 -干吗？
-What do you want? -I want you to have this.
-你想怎样？ -我要你收下这个
-What the heck is this? -Look closely.
-这是什么？ -仔细看
It's a scale.
是个鳞片
It's a contact lens.
这是隐形眼镜
It's a scale that fell from my eyes.
是从我眼睛掉下来的鳞片
What you said opened my eyes.
你的话让我觉醒啦
-This is a contact lens, man. -Yes.
-这是隐形眼镜 -对
-It's just like you said. -What?
-就像你说的那样 -什么？
You see…
你知道…
-What do you want? -You see…
-你想干什么？ -听我说
I'm a guy who has no wants and doesn't know what he wants to do.
我是一个没有欲望 也不知道自己想做什么的人
So?
所以？
-You're looking down on me. -I am not!
-你看不起我？ -我没有
-What's your problem? -I mean, there's nothing I want to do.
-你想干什么？ -我没有想做的事啊
I think everyone's like that.
大家应该都差不多
Really?
真的吗？
Okay, scale, goodbye.
好 鳞片 再见
Bye.
再见
What?
什么？
Hey, just wait up a second.
等我一下啦
Wait up a second.
等等
-We've had it with you, bitch! -Say something, Kotani!
-我们受够你啦 贱人 -说话啊 小谷
You little bitch…
你这个婊子…
Who said you could ignore us?
谁说你可以无视我们？
-Who said you could go? -Say something!
-谁说你可以离开？ -说话啊
I mean, we're talking to you, so talk to us!
我们在跟你说话 你要回话啊
-That's right! -Yes!
-没错 -对啊
-Feel good? -Get away from us!
-舒服吗？ -离我们远一点
You fucking creep!
怪人
-Why don't you say something? -What a bore!
-你怎么不说话？ -真无聊
Come on. Let's all get along, okay?
好啦 大家好好相处
Get your ass out of the girls' restroom!
滚出女厕
-Give me more! -Sebastian's coming!
-再来 -赛巴斯汀来啦
-Seriously? -The floor's wet out here too!
-真的吗？ -这边的地板也都湿啦
Dang! This is cold! This is really cold!
可恶 好冷 真的好冷
This is cold! It sure is cold, right?
好冷 对吗？
Soaking wet. We're both soaking wet.
湿透啦 我们都湿透啦
You know,
我说啊
can't you use your head more?
你就不能聪明点吗？
Haven't you ever thought of acting more like everyone else?
你没有想过要融入周围的环境吗？
That's right.
没错
If you changed just a little bit, things would be different.
如果你稍微改变一下 情况就会不一样啦
I don't think I can change anything.
我觉得我什么都改变不了
That's not true.
没那种事
It's impossible.
不可能
There's no way I can change anything.
我什么都改变不了
Giving up from the start is wrong!
一开始就放弃是不对的
I have wanted to change before.
我也曾经想过要改变
My mom remarried
我妈再婚
and I got a new dad,
我有个新爸爸
but I couldn't get close to him.
但我跟他一点都不亲
But I knew things couldn't be like that forever.
我知道不能再这样下去
So
所以
I did my absolute very best to call out to him.
我用尽全力叫了他
Dad!
爸爸
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
I married your mom,
虽然我娶了你妈
but I'm not your dad.
但我不是你爸
I was so ashamed.
我觉得很丢脸
I was so ashamed, I wanted to disappear.
因为太丢脸啦 很想干脆消失
I don't believe if you're courageous
我不相信只要有勇气
or if you open up your heart, things will change.
或者愿意敞开心房 情况就会改变
I mean,
因为
when I believe and open up my heart,
我曾经相信 并敞开心房
I only get hurt.
却只是受到伤害而已
Now, that's no way to talk. Right?
所以你不打算开口啦 对吗？
It's all right. I'm used to being bullied.
没关系 我习惯被霸凌啦
It's always been this way and probably always will be.
一直以来都是如此 或许以后也是如此
The hell you're used to it!
怎么可能有人会习惯？
You mean you're fine with
你是说你不介意
getting sprayed with water and your lunch tossed around? Are you?
被人泼水、丢便当？是这样吗？
How dare you decide that nothing will change?
你怎能一开始就断定 什么都不会改变？
At any rate,
总之
we've all got to live…
我们都必须
in this miserable school.
在这所可悲的学校活下去
Bando and them are pretty vindictive.
坂东那些女孩很会记仇的
They said they'd forgive me if I read at that shop.
她们说如果我在那家店看书 就会原谅我
At Goyokudo, right?
是在豪翼堂 对吗？
Only beautiful men and women can read there, right?
只有帅哥美女才能在那里看书？
They told me to go and read there today.
她们叫我今天去那里看书
Impossible.
不可能啦
They just want to laugh at you when you can't do it.
她们知道你做不到 只想嘲笑你
That's mean. So totally mean.
好过分 真的太过分啦
That's mean.
真过分
Let's go read there!
我们去那里看书
Hurry up.
快点
What're you stopping for?
你为什么停下来？
Anyone home?
有人在家吗？
Excuse me. Can I have some books?
不好意思 我能买一些书吗？
Some books? What kind of books?
一些书？什么样的书？
Oh, right. These are all books.
也对 这里都是书
Let's see…
我看看
Okay, from here
好 从这里
to here.
到这里
-From here to there? -Yes.
-从这里到那里？ -对
And can I leave them here on the shelf for a few days?
另外这些书能先放在架上几天吗？
I'd like to do some research too. Can I come here to read them?
我要查一些资料 我可以来这里看书吗？
-Sure. That's fine. -It is?
-当然可以 -真的吗？
Great! Hold on a second.
太好啦 等我一下
Let's go! Hurry!
走 快点
Go!
跟我来
She's going to come here to read. Will that be okay?
她要来这里看书 可以吗？
Okay.
好 没问题
You, hurry up and pay.
你快去付钱
-I have to pay? -You said you'd help.
-我要付钱？ -你说会帮忙的
Can I pay with this?
可以用这个吗？
A gold card!
金卡
Sure.
可以啊
-Hello!
-大家好
Together, we're Destiny!
我们是命运双人组
Nice to have you here!
请多多指教
At last, a new record was set!
终于出现新纪录啦
They read at the shop for two hours and ten minutes!
有人在那间书店读了2小时10分钟
I was dumbfounded!
令人瞠目结舌啊
-And who beat out Mariko Uehara? -Who?
-是谁打败了上原真理子？ -谁？
That supposedly creepy transfer student, Nobuko Kiritani!
那个转学生怪人小谷信子
How shocking!
太震惊了
Since he thought Goyokudo had lowered their standards,
他觉得豪翼堂的标准降低啦
Sebastian went and tried again.
赛巴斯汀又去试了一次
Sebastian? No way!
赛巴斯汀？怎么会？
-There's no way. -He'll never make it.
-不可能 -他做不到的
He's so stupid, it's sad.
他太蠢啦 真可怜
READING PROHIBITED EXCEPT FOR BEAUTIFUL MEN AND WOMEN
（禁止阅读 帅哥美女除外）
-Welcome!
-欢迎光临
Kotani!
小谷
Kotani! Look this way!
小谷 看这边
Look over here, Kotani!
小谷 看这里
Kotani, can you get a little closer to her?
小谷 你能再靠近她一点吗？
Good! Thank you. Now smile!
很好 谢谢 笑一个
Say "cheese"!
西瓜甜不甜？
NEW RECORD OF 2:10 READING SET BY TRANSFER STUDENT NOBUKO KOTANI
（新纪录 2小时10分钟 转学生小谷信子）
Goyokudo was so fun.
豪翼堂的事真有趣
They've got nothing else to do.
他们没别的事好做
And nobody noticed that we're the ones who--
没人注意到是我们…
Isn't this a great smell?
这很香吗？
Really nice, right? It's really popular.
很不错吗？现在很流行
Seriously. It's popular.
是真的 现在很流行
Nice! That was so totally nice!
很香 真的很香
You should be happier, man.
你应该要开心点才对
This will stop Kotani from getting bullied.
这样小谷就不会再被欺负啦
No, it won't. The bullying will start again in no time.
不可能 她过不久又会被欺负
Really? You think so?
真的吗？你那么想？
Listen.
听着
She was way down here.
她的地位本来在这里
If you want to make her popular, bringing her to normal isn't enough.
如果想让她受欢迎 光让她变回正常人是不够的
Unless she becomes top class, people's minds won't change.
除非她成为最顶层的人 否则大家的看法是不会变的
Idea! Okay then. Why don't we take Kotani
有啦 不然我们帮小谷
to that top-class level?
成为最顶层的人？
It's not that easy.
事情没那么简单
She might need to change on the inside too.
她的内在也需要改变
What's on the inside doesn't matter.
内在怎样并不重要
If everyone thinks you're beautiful, you're beautiful.
如果大家觉得你很美 你就是美女
If everyone wants something, the price goes up.
如果大家都想要某个东西 它的价格就会上涨
There are people who can make that stuff happen.
有些人就是专门计划这种事的
Cut that out!
别闹啦
Who is it that can make that happen?
是谁会专门计划这种事？
Those people over there.
那边那些人
What? My dad?
什么？我爸？
Don't be stupid. It's not one person.
别傻啦 不是只有一个人
It's people who think of ways to get people to spend more money.
是那些绞尽脑汁 想尽办法让人花钱的人
They make hits out of so-so songs.
他们让很普通的歌变成畅销金曲
They turn ordinary girls into pop idols.
把平凡的女孩变成流行偶像
They create long lines outside lousy ramen shops.
让人在难吃的拉面店外大排场龙
I guess you could call them "producers."
你可以称他们为改造者
Really? Then I'll do that.
真的吗？那我要当那种人
What?
什么？
Why don't we make Kotani the most popular person at school?
我们让小谷成为全校最受欢迎的人
What for?
为什么？
Remember what you said?
你不是说过吗？
Do what nobody's done before and explore our limits.
要做没人做过的事 探索我们的极限
Yes, but…
对啊 但是…
We'll be Kotani's producers!
我们当小谷的改造者
-We will? -Yes, we will.
-我们吗？ -就是我们
Wait a second. You're more the type who needs a producer yourself.
等等 我看你也是需要改造者的类型
That's fine too.
那好
-You be my producer too. -Why do I have to do that?
-你也当我的改造者 -我为什么要那么做？
Come on. Please! Producer Shuji Kiritani!
拜托啦 改造者桐谷修二
I finally see what my youth is for!
我的青春有救啦
Thanks, man.
拜托你啦
NEW RECORD OF 2:10 READING SET BY TRANSFER STUDENT NOBUKO KOTANI
（新纪录 2小时10分 转学生小谷信子）
I wonder if the world can be changed
不知道我们能不能
even by us guys.
改变这个世界
No.
不要
Why?
为什么？
I don't like lying.
我不喜欢说谎
Like at that bookstore. I mean, I'm not beautiful.
上次在书店也是 我又不漂亮
But that's how it is now.
但情况已经是这样啦
Who cares? What matters is everyone saw.
谁会在乎？重要的是大家看到啦
I'm going to tell everyone the truth about it.
我会把真相告诉大家
How come?
为什么？
-Don't do that. -Kotani!
-别这样吗 -小谷
Don't you think this is your chance?
你不觉得这是个好机会吗？
Unless you've got the will to change, you'll be bullied forever!
除非你愿意改变 否则永远都会被人欺负
You'll be torn up from the roots.
你会被连根拔起
Like that willow tree.
就像那棵柳树
Is that what you want?
那是你想要的吗？
I already told you!
我已经说过了
I can't change.
我无法改变
Wherever I go in this world, it's the same everywhere.
在这个世界上 不论我走到何处 情况都是一样的
It's all just a world where I don't belong.
这个世界没有我的容身之处
Then build it.
那就自己创造啊
A world you can live in…
我会替你打造
I'll build it for you.
一个你可以居住的世界
Did you hear that? Let him build it for you.
听到了吗？让他替你打造
I don't want that.
我不想要那样
Oh, well.
好吧
"Kotani."
“小谷
"I'll build it for you."
我会替你打造”
Dang! You're totally into this!
真是的 你很投入呀
Even if I am, it'll never happen if she's like that.
她那种态度 就算我很投入也不会成功
Word.
说得也是
Word…
好
Come on, Kiritani.
快过来 桐谷
-This? -Yes. The box on top of it.
-这个吗？ -对 上面那盒
You okay?
你还好吗？
-Come on. Clean it up. -What?
-好啦 来收拾 -什么？
What the heck is this?
这是什么玩意？
It's a monkey's paw!
这是猴爪
What's a monkey's paw?
什么是猴爪？
You don't know? It grants three wishes.
你不知道？它可以实现三个愿望
This does?
这个东西吗？
What luck! There's another one!
真幸运 又有一只
You can have it.
给你
When making wishes,
许愿的时候
they have to be said out loud!
必须大声说出来
I wish that my willow tree is alive and healthy somewhere else!
我希望我的柳树 在别的地方健康的活着
-What're you doing? -Whoa!
你在做什么？
-You scared me. -What's that? That's creepy!
-吓我一跳 -那是什么？好恶心
You can have it.
给你
Ribbit… What is this?
这是什么啊？
Apparently, it grants three wishes.
听说可以实现三个愿望
Really?
是吗？
I just made one wish, so it's got two more.
我刚许了一个愿所以现在还有两个
Wishes?
愿望？
What should I wish for?
我该许什么愿？
How should I know?
我怎么知道？
Get lots of hot chicks, make love to them, and get hammered.
找一堆辣妹上床 然后喝个烂醉
Don't be stupid!
别傻啦
Kiritani!
桐谷
Wait!
等一下
Give me your autograph.
帮我签名
-Hey! -Don't you have something to say?
-喂 -你不是有话要说吗？
Keeping quiet won't do you no good!
保持沉默对你没有好处
Don't get cocky just because you could read at that bookstore.
别以为你能在那间书店看书 就得意忘形啦
You listening?
你在听吗？
-Can't you hear us? -She's so stupid, she probably can't.
-你听到我们说话吗？ -她太笨啦 应该听不到
Unless you've got the will to change,
除非你愿意改变
you'll be bullied forever!
否则永远都会被人欺负
You'll be torn up from the roots.
你会被连根拔起
Say something, bitch!
说话啊 贱人
Hey!
可恶
-Kiritani! -What's wrong?
-桐谷 -怎么啦？
Bando and they are roughing up Kotani bad.
坂东她们把小谷欺负得很惨
Don't Bando and they have anything else to do?
坂东那群人没别的事好做吗？
Okay, I'm going.
好 那我先走啦
-You're leaving? -Yes.
-你要走啦？ -对
-Oh, okay. -Okay.
-好吧 -好
-Ciao!
-再见
Stop, Kotani!
站住 小谷
Stop!
别跑
Stop, damn it!
给我站住 该死
Get the fuck out of the way!
别挡路
Stop!
站住
Get up!
起来
Walk, damn it!
好好走 可恶
Come on! Walk!
你给我好好走路
-What's wrong? -Get up! You fucking creep!
-怎么啦？ -起来 怪人
Hey! Cut that out!
全都住手
Bitch! You fucking bitch!
贱人 你这个该死的贱女人
Shuji!
修二
Please…
拜托
Help me!
救我
Wherever I go in this world,
在这个世界上 不论我走到何处
it's the same everywhere.
情况都是一样的
It's all just a world…
这个世界
where I don't belong.
没有我的容身之处
-Kotani! You fucking bitch! -Stop, damn it!
-小谷 你这个该死的贱人 -站住 可恶！
-I've had it with you! -Stop!
-我受够你啦 -别跑
Would you just fucking stop?
快给我站住
Kotani! Stop!
小谷 别跑
Stop!
站住
Let go of me! What's your fucking problem, you geezer?
放开我 臭老头 你想怎样？
Fucking cut it out!
给我住手
What's your problem?
你想怎样？
DISGUSTING WOMEN CAN GO TO HELL AND DIE!
（讨厌的女人下地狱）
It's like I'm in a totally different world.
我好像进入一个完全不同的世界
I built this world.
我打造了这个世界
PESSIMISM NOT ALLOWED.
（远离悲观）
YOU CAN'T LIVE UNLESS YOU'RE TOUGH.
（坚强为生存法则）
NO KINDNESS, NO RIGHT TO LIVE.
（善良为做人原则）
May the principal's hair
愿校长的头发
grow thinner by the day,
一天比一天少
and in three years' time
并在三年后
may he please
他就会
become totally bald!
变成秃头
Oops! Did you see that?
糟糕 你看到啦？
Here. You can have it.
给你
I feel better now anyway.
我现在感觉好多啦
It should grant two more wishes.
它还能再实现两个愿望
Do you hate the principal?
你讨厌校长吗？
I hate his guts!
我恨死他啦
But since I work with him, I can't help being around him.
但因为我们一起共事 所以无法避不见面
It's such a pain.
真讨厌
When making wishes, they have to be said out loud!
许愿的时候一定要大声地说出来
Just making their hair fall out won't satisfy me.
让她们掉光头发并不能满足我
I want even worse things to happen to them.
我希望她们发生更糟糕的事
You're free to think anything you like.
你要怎么想都可以
You see, in my mind, I've killed dozens of people.
在我心中 我已经杀了数十人
Your mind is a very useful tool.
你的大脑是很实用的工具
Even if you don't do it,
就算没有付诸行动
just thinking it makes you feel better and helps you keep going.
光用想的就会让你好过一点 并帮助你继续走下去
All right then.
好
This thing works absolute wonders!
这玩意很灵哦
Be very careful what you wish for.
要小心许愿
I wish that
我希望
stupid Bando would disappear from this world!
坂东那个笨蛋会从这世上消失
That's that willow!
是那棵柳树
Does this mean
这表示
my wish came true?
我的愿望成真了吗？
Kotani?
小谷？
Kotani!
小谷
Kotani, get on!
小谷 快上来
Just hurry up and get on!
快点上来啊
What for?
为什么？
The tree they took out of here, it's still alive!
他们拔走的那棵树还活着
It'll be planted somewhere else!
它要被种在别的地方
Hurry up and get on!
快上来
That's it! There!
在那里
Yes!
好耶
Wow…
天啊
You're right.
是真的
Hurry up and grab on. Hurry!
抓紧我 快
I bet that willow never thought it would travel on the water.
我猜那棵柳树从没想过 自己会在水上旅行
You've got to live.
一定要活下去
Because you never know what'll happen.
否则不会知道接下来会发生什么事
I never thought
我没想过
there'd be a place where we can start our lives over again.
会有一个能让我们重新开始的地方
Yes.
是呀
I wonder,
不知道…
if I could become a big tree.
我能不能成为一棵大树
A tree so big…
一棵强壮到
that nobody can pull it up.
没有人能拔起的大树
You've got no choice.
你别无选择
Oh, right.
对啦
Here.
给你
Oh, that? It was torn.
那地方本来破啦
Cancel my wish that Bando disappear from this world.
收回我希望坂东消失在 这个世界的愿望
I will…
我会…
live in this world that Bando is in.
活在有坂东的世界里
Dinner's ready.
晚餐准备好啦
What's that disgusting thing?
那个恶心的东西是什么？
Mr. Hirayama, this is called a monkey's paw.
大叔 这叫做猴爪
It'll grant any wish you make.
它会实现你的任何愿望
Don't be ridiculous.
少胡说八道
Okay! I've made up my mind.
好 我决定啦
May there be world peace!
我希望世界和平
There! It's done!
好 我许完愿望啦
Click!
打开
Wonder if they'll have news that peace broke out in the Near East.
不知道会不会有 远东地区恢复和平的消息
Don't be ridiculous.
别胡说啦
I'm serious!
我是认真的
This thing can grant one more wish,
这个东西还可以实现一个愿望
so go ahead and make one.
你去许一个愿
-What? Me? -Go right ahead.
-什么？我？ -许个愿
Let's see… Okay.
这个…好
Please cancel that wish for world peace.
请收回世界和平的愿望
Hey, man!
喂
I got us world peace, so what did you do that for?
我才让世界和平 你为什么许那种愿望啊？
Yes, maybe you did.
也许是那样
Maybe so.
也许
Your wish really may have come true.
你的愿望可能真的实现啦
You know, there may have been total world peace for three seconds.
说不定刚刚世界和平了3秒钟
You don't believe that!
你不相信我
-You don't believe that at all! -Yes, I do!
-你根本不相信 -我相信啊
Here you go. Extra-large serving.
来 给你个大碗的
How things turn out is sometimes frightening.
事情的发展有时很令人害怕
Before I knew it, I'd decided to be the producer for Nobuko.
回过神来 我已经决定要当 信子的改造者啦
Top secret!
最高机密
It's top secret!
这是最高机密
Don't go shouting it at the top of your lungs.
那你还喊那么大声
You know, shouldn't we, like, give Nobuko
我们是不是该给信子
a stage name or a nickname or something?
取个艺名或绰号之类的？
Yes, that's probably true.
是啊 这样比较好
What's your name again?
你叫什么名字？
Nobuko?
信子？
-Shut up.
-闭嘴
-Nobu… Shut up! Nobuko…
-信子 -信…闭嘴啦 信子
-Nobuko. -Nobuta.
-野猪
-Nobuta? No… -Nobuta?
-野猪？不行 -野猪？
-I like "Nobuta." -What?
-我喜欢“野猪” -什么？
How come?
为什么？
-What's this? -Don't show him that!
-那是什么？ -别给他看
Sometimes, I wonder why in the world I'm getting carried away with these guys
有时候 我怀疑自己 为什么要跟这些家伙瞎闹
and totally regret it.
并且感到非常后悔
But then, this is
但这只不过是…
just another game.
另一场游戏
What's the point unless I have fun?
如果不开心 还有什么意义？
But
但是
at that time,
那时候
I had absolutely no idea…
我完全不知道
DIE
（去死）
Soon, we'd be fighting against the incredibly deep and dark thing
我们很快就要对抗阴险黑暗的…
that is human malice.
人类恶意
You exist. That's all you need to think about.
你只需要记住自己是存在的
-Ugly pig! -We're just saying what's true!
-丑猪 -我们说的都是实话
-Let's end this. -End what?
-我们结束这一切 -结束什么？
This whole thing about producing her.
改造她的事
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey
字幕翻译：张欣怡